Dr. Po-Hsun Tseng

6+ years experience of large-scale software development with C programming on the Linux system throughout my Ph.D. journey.

Seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity with low-level system programming (eg. device driver, Linux kernel, CPU architecture) to apply my skills at a fabless company.



CONTACT

zengbs@gmail.com

+886 966 587 832

Hsinchu, Taiwan

https://github.com/zengbs

SKILLS

Programming

Bash scripting System programming **CUDA**

Pvthon

Operating System

Linux - user Linux - kernel

Architecture

ARM architecture

Software & Tools

Git Vim Gdb **Valgrind**

Languages

Chinese (native) **English - writing English - speaking English - listening**

English - reading

EDUCATION

6 08/2016 - 06/2022

Ph.D. in Computational Physics

- Developed and implemented a new algorithm to reduce numerical error by a factor of $10^6\,$ compared to conventional one. See Fig. 16 in ${\tt https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130}.$
- Actively collaborated with Dr. Chiueh/Dr. Schive (see the Section References) to develop the new algorithm.

WORK HISTORY

12/2014 - 01/2016

♥ TDK corporation, Singapore

Design surface acoustic wave(SAW) filters

6 08/2013 - 08/2014

Military Service

EDUCATION

1 09/2011 - 07/2013

♀ National Taiwan University, Taiwan

1 09/2006 - 07/2011

Q National Central University, Taiwan

M.Sc. in Physics

Circuit designer

B.Sc. in Mathematics

SOFT SKILLS

Nonverbal communication

Active listening

Open mindedness

Patience

Mutual respect

Teamwork

Brainstorming

Collaboration

GENERAL SKILLS

Numerical algorithm

Large-scale project

cscope

makefile

GNU autotools

PUBLICATIONS

An adaptive mesh, GPU-accelerated, and error minimized special relativistic hydrodynamics code

Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsi-Yu Schive, Tzihong Chiueh

Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society Vol. 504, pp. 3298-3315
https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130

The symmetry problem of the Fermi and eROSITA bubbles: A proof-of-concept study
Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang, Hsi-Yu Schive, Tzihong Chiueh

2022 preprint

TALKS

 An adaptive-mesh, GPU-accelerated, and optimally error-controlled special relativistic hydrodynamics code Oral (remote), American Center for Physics College Park, U.S.A

Mar. 2021

A new and accurate code for simulating special relativistic hydrodynamics
 Oral, Annual Meeting of the Physical Society of Taiwan, NPTU.

Feb. 2020

REFERENCES

- Please send an appointment letter to request a call. 😃
- Dr. Tzihong Chiueh

Distinguished Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- chiuehth@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- +886 2 3366 8628
- Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- hyschive@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- **** +886 2 3366 8644
- Dr. Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astronomy, National Tsing Hua University

- Hsinchu 30013, Taiwan
- hyang@phys.nthu.edu.tw
- **4886** 3 574 2953